(773) 800-ZEVG • Evanston, IL 60203 zevgoldberg [at] gmail.com responsive HTML version at <u>resume.zevgoldberg.com</u>

# Zev Goldberg

Senior Software Engineer | Guitar FX Mad Scientist



## **Summary**

Thoughtful, thorough and inclusive. With more than 25 years of experience, I am looking to be a good citizen on the internet, and build the next generation of web applications. I strive to understand end-users, while gathering consensus from stakeholders, UX and Product teams to build interfaces that are perceivable, operable, understandable and robust. I am a noise-maker and noisemaker-maker.

# **Specialties**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, component frameworks, REST API, Single Page Applications, React.js, Next.js, Svelte, Typescript, SCSS/Sass, Jest, Storybook, Chromatic, Webpack, Universal Design, UX/UI, accessibility, responsive layout, guitar FX, and skronky bloopy noises.

# **Experience**

#### **GRAINGER**

CHICAGO, IL | APR 2015-SEP 2024 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

- HTML, CSS, SCSS/Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Svelte, React, TypeScript, Next.js,
  StoryBook, Jest, Webpack, Snyk, Github Actions/Workflows, REST API, microservices
- $\_\,$  Develop components and pages for e-commerce application
- Convert legacy pages to faster and more robust SPAs
- \_ Participate in regular on-call rotation for troubleshooting issues with released code
- \_ Write documentation for components in Storybook for other developer teams
- Define accessibility requirements and shape approach for implementation of UI components
- Implement mechanism for onsite employees to provide feedback on internal search results
- \_ Automate processes with GitHub Actions and Workflows, Bash scripts

#### SEARS IR LABS

CHICAGO, IL | MAY 2014-MAR 2015 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Bootstrap, Less, Angular-UI, Grunt, Underscore, Github
- Develop gamified learning management application
- Convert UX documents and mock-up images into functioning sections of the application

#### MINT CHIP

SKOKIE, IL | MARCH 2014-MAY 2014 | SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Wordpress, Git, Beanstalk
- Develop and troubleshoot responsive Wordpress sites for SMB clients

#### CRITICAL MASS

CHICAGO, IL | DECEMBER 2013-FEBRUARY 2014 | SENIOR DEVELOPER

- \_ Web Performance Tools, Google PageSpeed Tools, YSlow, ImageOptim
- Develop strategies and plans to measure and improve load times and perceived performance of existing websites

#### CHICAGO TRIBUNE

CHICAGO, IL | APRIL 2012-NOVEMBER 2013 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, responsive layout, touch-enabled, cross-browser, device-agnostic, SVN, Photoshop, InDesign
- $_{-}\,$  Develop major metropolitan online newspaper as a device-agnostic SPA
- Convert requirements documents and mock-up images into layouts and functioning sections of the website
- \_ Interview and onboard frontend engineer candidates

## JSPACE.COM, LLC

CHICAGO, IL | NOVEMBER 2010-APRIL 2012 | WEB DEVELOPER

- HTML, CSS, Smarty, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Modernizr, NetBeans, Subversion, Photoshop, PHP, Zend, MySQL
- Lead frontend development of HTML and CSS for a large social network, news, venue/city guide and dating site
- Convert requirements documents and mock-up images into reusable templates and functioning sections of the website

#### CHICAGO SUN-TIMES

CHICAGO, IL | OCTOBER 2010-NOVEMBER 2010 | FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

- \_ HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop
- Migrate several classified ads systems into the new one, maintaining the latest look-and-feel styles

#### MYWRIGLEYVILLE.COM

CHICAGO, IL | MAY 2010-AUGUST 2010 | WEB DEVELOPER

- LAMP, Joomla, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, ColdFusion, Photoshop, Illustrator, social media, Android
- Develop and maintain company's extensive web presence and partner websites

### EXTENDED CARE CONSULTING

EVANSTON, IL | MAY 2006-APRIL 2010 | SENIOR DATABASE AND APPLICATION DEVELOPER

- LAMP, Joomla, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Prototype, Scriptaculous, etc.), Ajax, Excel, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, SubVersion, Fiery Print Server, bash/Python scripting
- Design, develop, code, test and support online database applications with multiple access levels, user management, custom user interface, reporting and graphs used by more than 300 people spanning several departments
- Design, develop and maintain a custom CMS for more than thirty websites for all Extended Care nursing facilities
- Provide complete graphics services for promotional materials and newsletters,
  including layout, copy-editing, printing and liaison to professional printing services

# **Education**

## COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO

Chicago, IL | 1994–1998 | Computer Animation and Film

## UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO

Chicago, IL | 1993–1994 | Computer Science